Balaji Sundaramoorthy







linkedin.com/in/balaji-sundaramoorthy-899a7a152

https://balajisundar13.github.io/Balaji Portfolio.github.io/

Summary

Process-oriented Data Analyst with 3+ years of experience with total 5 years of IT experience in a Product company. Skilled in Data Analysis, SQL, Spreadsheets, Tableau, R, Data cleansing and Data Visualization with strong communication skills. Experienced in interacting with customers on daily basis to understanding the business objective. Led a QA team for manual and automation testing.

Skills

• Data Analysis • Spreadsheets • SQL • PostgreSQL • Excel • AWS • Linux • R for Data Analysis • Data Visualization • Git/GitHub • Business Analysis • Data Cleansing • HTML/CSS • Data Integration

Work Experience



Data Analyst in Success4, Inc

Jul 2019 - Present (3 years 7 months)

- · As a Data/Business Analyst. I work with Data & Statistics. Meetings with clients on regular basis to understand business difficulties and develop specifications based on their demands. Delivered multiple
- Successfully integrated 15+ different types of data integration ex: Salesforce, Zendesk, Jira, Mix panel, SharePoint etc...
- Created 100+ Business Intelligence Visualization reports for multiple customers.

Software Engineer in DecisionMinds Pvt.Ltd

Jan 2018 - Jun 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Build a Customer Success Product, Worked on Development and Testing. Found and reported 1000+ functionality and UI bugs during the testing phase.

Education



AVC College Of Engineering

Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2012 - 2016

Licenses & Certifications



Google Professional Data Analytics Certificate - Coursera | Google



AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Issued Oct 2020 - Expires Oct 2023